《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情回顾
NARRATOR: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
这里是太空堡垒帕伽索斯...
MAN: This is the Battlestar Pegasus
与声称是卡拉狄加的飞船通话
to the ship claiming to be the Galactica.
请回答
Please respond.
帕伽索斯?  怎么可能?
Pegasus? How could that be?
他们的整支舰队早已被摧毁了
The entire fleet was destroyed.
凯恩上将
Adm. Cain.
我谨代表帕伽索斯的官员...
On behalf of the officers and the crew of the Pegasus,
欢迎大家回归殖民舰队
welcome back to the Colonial Fleet.
那支舰队由两艘母舰...
The Cylon fleet is composed of two base ships,
外加大约12艘补给船组成
about a dozen or so support ships
还有一艘未知的巨舰
and one large vessel that we are still unable to identify.
我所感兴趣的就是这艘巨舰
It's this large ship here that I'm interested in.
我要合并船员
I'm going to integrate the crews.
你说过你无意干涉我的指挥权
I thought you said you had no desire to interfere with my command.
我是帕伽索斯上的轮机长拉尔德
I'm Laird, Pegasus Deck Chief.
你是航空工程师?
You're an aeronautical engineer?
以前是
Yeah, I was.
那你其实是平民?
So you're really a civilian?
我当时在斯库拉上 随后被帕伽索斯接走了
I was on the Scylla, and we got picked up by the Pegasus.
当时发生了一些事...
Things happen.
我还有多少时间?
How much time do I have?
几周  能支撑一个月
Weeks, a month at the outside.
我还能工作么?
Will I be able to work?
除非癌细胞扩散到了你的脑部...
Unless the cancer goes to your brain. If that happens, you...
我们也有一名赛昂囚犯
CAIN: We have our own Cylon prisoner.
她明显被虐待过 折磨过
NO. 6: She's obviously been abused. Tortured.
你会帮她么  盖尤斯?
Will you help her, Gaius?
如果你真想靠近它们...
You really want to get close,
就要用我们…
you got to use the stealth ship
卡拉狄加的黑鸟号
we constructed aboard Galactica.
碳基复合材料?  要在雷达上看到它可就难了
APOLLO: Carbon composite? It's gonna be hard as hell to see on dradis.
星芭儿 你不用参与此次任务了
Starbuck, you're off this mission.
监视装备?
A surveillance package?
去驾驶黑鸟号...
Go get the Blackbird.
多照几张赛昂飞船的漂亮图片
Take some pretty pictures of our Cylon ship.
桑恩是谁啊?
Who the hell's this Thorne?
桑恩中尉  长官
GAGE: Lt. Thorne, sir.
你们的机器小妞要当坐骑了
Your little robot girl's in for quite a ride.
别碰她!
TYROL: Get off her!
你们俩都他妈别动!
...either of you frakking move! Don't move!
他们的各项罪名都成立...
They've been found guilty on all counts.
她要以谋杀和叛国两项罪名处决他们
She's going to execute them both for murder and treason.
卡拉狄加派出了蝮蛇战机和一架猛禽号
Galactica is launching Vipers and a Raptor.
为什么你要派出蝮蛇战机?
Why are you launching Vipers?
我要把我的人带回来
I'm getting my men.
派出待战机
Launch the alert Vipers.
卡拉狄加  我是小凯 帕伽索斯的蝮蛇战机正向我袭来
KAT: Galactica, Kat. I've got inbound Pegasus Vipers coming right at me.
请求指示
Request instructions.
他们得保护自己
We've gotta let 'em defend themselves.
我们应掉转主炮指向帕伽索斯
We should turn our main batteries on Pegasus.
卡拉狄加  我是小凯 请求自由射击
KAT: Galactica, Kat. Request weapons free.
下命令吧
We need your help.
小凯  这里是卡拉狄加 不准首先开火
DUALLA: Kat, Galactica. Do not fire unless fired upon.
重复  不准首先开火
I repeat, do not fire unless fired upon.
卡拉狄加  我是小凯 他们在向我们挑衅
Galactica, Kat. They're really frakking with us out here!
卡拉狄加  我是热狗
HOTDOG: Galactica, Hotdog.
我刚与其中一架擦身而过
One of them just pulled into my kill slot.
在火力范围内 锁定
HOTDOG: Got him in range. Locking on.
卡拉狄加 准备战斗
Galactica, standing by...
热狗  小心身后 他就在你后面
PILOT 1: Hotdog, watch yourself, he's right behind you!
回避动作  一群混蛋!
HOTDOG: Evasive action, come on! Frakking frakkers!
好了  这样你只能改变航线了
Okay. You're gonna have to break your course now.
纳休 我是帕伽索斯 不要首先开火
HOSHI: Narcho, Pegasus. Do not fire first.
斯丁  这里是帕伽索斯  命令你解除阿达玛上尉的职务
HOSHI: Stinger, Pegasus. You are ordered to relieve Capt. Adama of duty
并协助攻击卡拉狄加
and aid in the attack mission on Galactica.
交出你的武器  上尉  你被撤职了
STINGER: Your weapon, Captain. You're relieved.
摇滚明星 这里是帕伽索斯
HOSHI: Rock Star, this is Pegasus.
你说什么?
What's your call position?
...在飞翼附近  回来！ 回来！
PILOT 2:... around your wing. Come around, come around!
请准许去机尾    批准了
Permission to go aft. Granted.
这家伙想对我射击 他就在我正上方
KAT: This one attempted to shoot at me. He's right on top of me!
快躲开 你太靠近了
HOSHI: Break away! Break away! You're too close!
快躲开
Come on, break.
妈的  他们好碍眼啊!
Frak me! They're all over us!
卡拉狄加  请求自由射击
Galactica, request weapons free.
他们又要来了
KAT: They're coming around for another pass.
重复  请求自由射击
Repeat, request weapons free!
拜托  星芭儿
Come on, Starbuck.
但愿你就在附近
Tell me you're out there somewhere.
怎么搞的?
What the hell is...
我是星芭儿
STARBUCK: Starbuck here.
到底怎么回事
What the hell is going on?
警报 看你后面
HOTDOG: Warning! Watch your back!
雷达发现目标
GAETA: Dradis contact!
一可疑战机靠近我军上方
A single bogey and it's nearly on top of us!
查明目标
Identify.
无应答器  无识别码
No transponders, no recognition codes,
一定是赛昂突袭机  长官
it has to be a Cylon Raider, sir.
上将  那一定是突袭机
Admiral, sir, she's gotta be a Raider.
怎么他妈让它靠得这么近才被发现?
Well, how the frak did it get in so close without being detected?
不知道  长官 我肯定它是从天而降
I don't know, sir. I assure you it came out of nowhere.
帕伽索斯 请求垂直交叉
PILOT 3: Pegasus, request vertical cross.
好吧
Right.
到处都是敌机 上尉 正在接近中
PILOT 4: They're just everywhere, Captain. They're coming up close!
召回蝮蛇战机 掉转航向
Recall the Vipers, bring the ship about
准备与敌机交火
and prepare to engage the enemy.
隶属帕伽索斯的蝮蛇战机紧急回撤
HOSHI: All Pegasus Vipers, all Pegasus Vipers, emergency recall.
一架赛昂突袭机从上方袭来
There's a Cylon Raider right on top of you.
隶属卡拉狄加的蝮蛇战机注意
DUALLA: Attention, all Galactica Vipers, you got a Cylon Raider
一架赛昂突袭机袭来
coming right at you.
你等着吧  混蛋!    跟着我!
There you are, you bastard. On my lead!
加大油门  横向右转
Break right, full power, X- axis climb!
蝮蛇战机  我是星芭儿 不要开火
Starbuck to all Vipers, do not fire.
重复  不要开火
Repeat, do not fire.
我是友军
I'm a friendly, okay?
我们都是朋友
We're all friendlies,
大家都友好相处吧
so let's just be friendly.
那不是突袭机 是你们的隐形战机
That's no Raider, that's that stealth ship of yours.
是谁驾驶的? 没准许它起飞啊?
It was flying and it wasn't cleared to launch.
这可问倒我了 我现在只是一名乘客
You got me. I'm just a passenger back here.
卡拉狄加  我是小凯 那是黑鸟号
Galactica, Kat. It's the Blackbird, Galactica.
重复  是黑鸟号
KAT: Repeat, it's the Blackbird.
黑鸟号怎么跑到那里去了?
What the hell is the Blackbird doing out there?
都不要开火
HOTDOG: All pilots hold fire.
星芭儿在几小时前开走的
It's Starbuck. She launched in the Blackbird a couple hours ago,
说是为凯恩上将试飞而发射的
said she was running flight tests for Adm. Cain.
听起来不太可能
That doesn't sound likely.
她又玩命地耍了一把
Another one of her crazy-assed stunts.
谢天谢地
Thank the gods!
可不么  给我接通帕伽索斯
You can say that again. Get me Pegasus.
我是帕伽索斯指挥官  请讲
This is Pegasus Actual, go ahead.
是鸣金收兵 还是自相残杀
We can either stand-down or we could start shooting at each other.
你决定
It's your call.
上将
Admiral.
等下
Wait one.
我们在接收数据 上将
We're receiving a download, Admiral.
那是赛昂舰队啊
That is the Cylon fleet.
这些是我们侦察行动的成果么?
Are these from our recon mission?
不是  长官 侦察任务早已取消
No, sir. The recon mission was aborted.
这些是黑鸟号传来的
These are from Blackbird.
瑟瑞丝...
Thrace.
她单枪匹马就完成了侦察任务
She took off and did the whole recon mission alone.
我的天  看看这些照片  杰克
My gods, look at these shots, Jack.
她离他们近在咫尺 他们却毫无察觉
She put her nose right up their backsides, and they never even knew it.
上将  阿达玛指挥官还在线上
Admiral, I still have Commander Adama on the line,
我们的战机也请求进一步指示
and our fighters are still requesting instructions.
要他们继续作战么?
Should they resume the attack?
好吧  共同撤退
All right. Joint recall.
两艘船都降回二级戒备
Both ships stand-down to Condition Two.
并且你要亲自到我这里报到
Then I want you to report to me directly. In person.
我可不想束手就擒
I have no intention of cooling my heels in your brig.
好吧
Fine.
中立地带  殖民者一号 不带随从
Neutral ground. Colonial One, no aides.
15分钟内见
Be there in 15 minutes.
降回二级戒备
Stand-down, Condition Two.
原来你们在那里
There you are.
我们先把丑话说在前面
ROSLIN: Let's start this by admitting an ugly truth.
今天所发生的事都归因于
What happened out there today was the result of failure in leadership
这房间里各位领导的失职
of everyone in this room.
我们是这支舰队的领导者
We are the leaders of this fleet.
因此更要以身作则
As such, we need to set an example.
我们不能再让彼此间的…
We cannot continue to let the conflicts between us...
我们就直说吧
Oh, let's cut through the hand-holding, shall we?
他的两名部下为保护一个赛昂人 而杀害了我的一名军官
Two of his men murdered one of my officers
而杀害了我的一名军官
while protecting a Cylon.
他们有罪 他们对此供认不讳
They're guilty. They admitted it.
我有足够的权力按照法规
And under regulations I have complete authority
裁决他们  判决他们
to try, convict and sentence them.
你我都清楚 他们所犯的罪是死罪
And you and I both know that the penalty for that crime is death.
上将  简单地说
Admiral, surely the spirit of the law
就地正法并非是法律的要旨
requires something more here than summary executions.
你俩在过去的6个月中 就在干这些事吗?
Is this what the two of you have been doing for the past six months?
讨论殖民地法律的合理性
Debating the finer points of Colonial law? Well, guess what?
现在是战争时期
We're at war.
我们没时间对此问题进行学术讨论
And we don't have the luxury of academic debate over these issues.
你想开门见山  那好
You want to cut through it, fine.
你有帕伽索斯 他有卡拉狄加
You have Pegasus, he has Galactica.
两艘全副武装的强大战舰
Two heavily armed, very powerful warships.
想来帕伽索斯一直是所向披靡吧
Now, I am sure that Pegasus would prevail in any fight.
我看够戗
I wouldn't count on that.
但当然你们也会被重创
ROSLIN: But certainly there'd be heavy damage,
伤亡惨重
and you'd take significant casualties.
所以是拼个你死我活
So you can go out there and fight it out with Galactica,
还是妥协退让
or you can compromise.
只有这两个选择
And those are the only two options on the table, period.
就你们这样还能活到今天 我真是做梦也想不到
How the two of you have survived this long, I will never know.
好吧 我已从瑟瑞丝中尉那里得到了...
All right. Lt. Thrace has sent me detailed recon information
那支赛昂舰队的具体情报 我要摧毁他们
on the Cylon fleet. I want that fleet.
还要卡拉狄加协助我 我能做出的让步就这么多
And I need Galactica to get it. So I'm willing to go this far.
在那之后再执行死刑
I'll suspend the executions until after the attack.
我还要让他们现在回到卡拉狄加
I want them back on Galactica.
你想要干什么该我屁事
I don't give a damn what you want.
你没以身拭法算你他妈走运
You're frakking lucky you're not staring at your own warrant.
摧毁赛昂舰队先放在首位
The destruction of the Cylon fleet will take priority
其他事情先放一边
over all other considerations.
事后我们再回到这里解决这件事
After that, we will meet back here and we will resolve this issue.
谢谢
Thank you.
稍息  中尉 上前来
Stand at ease, Lieutenant, and come forward.
看起来你今天过得不一般呐
It seems you've had quite a day.
我提拔你为上尉
I'm promoting you to Captain.
任命你为帕伽索斯的空军队长
I'm making you Commander of the Pegasus Air Group.
你要提拔我?
You're promoting me?
我要的是有胆识的空军队长
I need a CAG with guts and initiative
可以制定计划攻击这支舰队的人
to plan and lead the attack on this fleet.
我本以为斯丁是块料
Now, I thought Stinger was that man,
可他让阿达玛上尉
but he managed to let Capt. Adama contact you
在他的眼皮底下与你取得联系
and pull off that fly-by stunt right under his nose,
所以他出局了
so he's out.
那阿达玛上尉呢  长官?
And Capt. Adama, sir?
我其实就差这么一点就关他禁闭了
Truth be told, I came this close to throwing him in the brig,
但也不好定他的罪
but I couldn't exactly charge him and not you,
所以就禁止他飞行了
so I've just revoked his flight status.
我想让他加入我的队伍  长官
I want him on my team, sir.
你总是能要风得风么?
And do you always get what you want?
大多数时候是的  长官
Most of the time, sir.
好
Good.
我也一样
Me, too.
好  可以把他交给你
All right, you can have him.
听说你想返回卡布里卡?
I hear you want to return to Caprica.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
那里还有我们的人
We have people back there still alive.
说的对  应该搭救他们 我完全同意
Yes, and they deserve to be saved. I absolutely agree.
事实上  我还想采取进一步措施
In fact, I will go one step further
我们的最终目标是...
and I will say that our ultimate goal
返回12殖民地
is that we should return to the 12 Colonies
把赛昂人赶出我们的家园
and kick the Cylons the frak out of our homes.
你说怎么样  上尉?
What do you think of that, Captain?
好主意  长官
I think that's the best idea I've heard all day, sir.
恐怕解决此事的办法只有一个
I'm afraid this can only end one way.
你只能杀了她
You've gotta kill her.
说什么傻话呢
What the hell are you talking about?
像她一样 我们还是有话直说
Like she said, let's cut through it.
你们二人
The two of you
今天都可以兵戎相见
were willing to go to war today.
你说她会善罢甘休么?
Do you think she's going to step down from that?
她会等待时机
She's gonna bide her time
干掉你 这是肯定的
and hit you the first chance she gets. That's a given.
我不想把这些强加给你  比尔  但她是一个危险人物
I hate to lay this on you, Bill, but she is dangerous,
而你能做的就是先下手为强
and the only thing that you can do is to hit her before she hits you.
我可不是刺客
I'm not an assassin.
说的对
No.
你不是一名刺客 你是一名…
You're not an assassin. You are a Colonial officer
誓死保卫这支殖民舰队的军官
who has taken an oath to protect this fleet.
你觉得她一旦除掉了你
What do you think that she is going to do with the civilian fleet
将会如何处置这支民用舰队?
once she has eliminated you?
你知道我是对的
You know I'm right.
只是不愿意去面对
You just don't wanna face it.
看来要天下大乱了
Has the whole world gone mad?
你的体液和电解液的浓度趋于稳定
COTTLE: Your fluid and electrolyte levels are stable.
我想婴儿不会有事
I think the baby's gonna be fine.
但你有一根肋骨骨折了
You do have a cracked rib, though,
发丝状的裂缝 也就是说有一段时期 你会疼痛难忍
a hairline fracture, which means it's gonna hurt like hell for a while.
但我没发现那次袭击所造成的任何永久性损伤
But I'm not seeing any signs of permanent damage from the attack.
"袭击"?  我们把那件事叫做"袭击"了?
The attack. Is that what we're calling it now?
不是我们开始叫的
They were not from the Galactica.
是从帕伽索斯上传来的    那又有什么区别?
They were from the Pegasus. So what?
西洛和上士怎么样了?
What about Helo and the Chief?
我听传闻说他们会被处死
I heard a rumor they're gonna be executed.
我不会坐视不管的
I'm not gonna let that happen.
那你又能怎样?
Well, how're you gonna do that?
难道不是凯恩上将掌权么?
Isn't Adm. Cain in command?
你所遭受的一切...
What happened to you...
都是不可饶恕的
COTTLE: Was unforgivable.
在我当值的船上发生的事
...happened aboard my ship, on my watch,
就是我的责任
and it's my responsibility.
所以你要知道 我个人来讲感到很抱歉
So I just want you to know that I personally apologize.
等她无大碍后 再回牢房里吧
See that she's okay, then back into her cell.
咱们不是早就该死了么?
Aren't we supposed to be dead?
上将说一小时内执行 现在至少两小时了
Admiral said execution in an hour. It's been at least two.
我倒是无所谓
Hey, I'm not complaining.
[ 已确认身份 ]
COMPUTER: ID confirmed.
你们是要多傻有多傻啊
So, just how many different kinds of stupid are you?
傻到家了
More than we can count.
怎么了  上尉?
What's going on, Captain?
好消息是你们还活着
Good news, you're not dead yet.
坏消息是缓刑 并不是特赦
Bad news, it's a delay, not a pardon.
要展开大行动了
There's a big op coming up,
所以行刑队要先等一等
and the firing squad's on hold till it's over.
老头子竭力为你们辩护 结果是…
Yeah, the old man went to the mat for you guys on this one, and then some.
我们就差这么一点 就和帕伽索斯交战了
We were this close to a shooting war with the Pegasus.
真没想到
Frak me.
出了什么事? 敌人不是赛昂人么?
What the hell's going on? I thought the Cylons were the enemy.
恩  现在换成我们了
Yeah. Now it's us.
怎么了  盖尤斯?
What's wrong, Gaius?
没什么
Nothing.
我只是...
I suppose I just
失去了兴趣
lost interest.
对我失去了兴趣?        不  不是你
In me? No, not in you. In...
对这里  这个地方
In this. In this place.
看来真是没什么让我留恋的了
I suppose I just don't really miss it anymore.
知道我留恋什么吗?
You know what I miss?
运动
Sports.
你在开玩笑?
You're joking.
不
No.
我以前常在金字塔比赛开始前去球场里
I used to go to the pyramid court just before game time.
倒卖两张黄牛票
Scalp two tickets.
如果我掐准时间 就会坐在喇叭下面
If I timed it right, I'd just be sitting down at the horn.
后仰
Sit back.
让人群的能量侵袭我全身
Let the energy of the crowd flow over me.
他们情绪的波动...
Waves and waves of emotion.
像电流一样
Like electric current.
为什么要带两张票
Why did you get two tickets?
你我各一张
One for me and one for you.
我知道你永远不会陪我去
I knew I'd never get you to go.
金字塔比赛对你来说是低级趣味 但是…
Pyramid was far too lowbrow for you. But...
我喜欢那种你在我身边的感觉
I always liked to feel that you were there with me.
[ 已确认身份 ]
COMPUTER: ID confirmed.
至少你让它进食了
Well, I see that you got it to eat.
看来也算是有所进步
That's progress, I suppose.
能让她翻过来求饶么?
Can you get it to roll over, beg?
看它能否认出这是什么
See what it can make of these.
这东西曾坐在我们中间
You know, this thing used to sit in our mess
吃我们的食物 听我们讲故事
and eat our food and listen to our stories.
是不是? 你就坐在那里
Didn't you? You just sat there,
听我们说话 假装是我们的朋友 是不是?
listening to us, pretending to be our friend. Didn't you?
上将  求你
Admiral, please!
此时与研究对象的任何直接接触
Any physical contact with the subject will only help
都会防碍我的工作
to set my efforts back at this point.
查明那艘船
Find out about that ship.
我想死
I want to die.
能帮我么?
Will you help me do that?
求你杀了我
Will you kill me, please?
我正追赶这里的工作节奏
I'm just still getting up to speed on the way you do things around here,
但我肯定这些战机 在发动攻击之前
but I'm reasonably sure that we can have all the birds in the air
会全部修理好
for the attack thing, sure.
是这样的  长官
I mean, yes, sir.
谢谢你  轮机长
Thank you, Chief.
嗨 嗨
MAN 1: Hey! Hey!
行了
MAN 2: I got it, I got it.
帮把手 凯莉
MAN 1: Give me a hand. Cally.
拉尔德不是军人  是吧?
Laird's not military, is he?
是的  长官
No, sir.
他曾是斯库拉上的
He was a civilian aeronautical engineer
民用航空工程师
on a ship called the Scylla.
平民?
Civilian?
知道他怎么到了帕伽索斯上的么?
Do you know how he got on the Pegasus?
传闻帕伽索斯曾有一支民用舰队
Scuttlebutt is that the Pegasus used to have a civilian fleet,
但那舰队出了意外
but something happened to them.
谢谢
Thank you.
拉尔德曾是斯库拉上的人?
Laird's ship was the Scylla.
斯库拉是一艘民用运输船
The Scylla was a civilian transport.
我们在赛昂人袭击一星期以后
We found her and a few other civies
发现了它和一些民用船
about a week after the attack.
那些船不错
They were good ships.
甚至配有超光速驱动器和武器
FTL drives and weapons, even.
许多帕伽索斯会用得着的备用配件
A lot of potential spare parts that we could use on Pegasus.
因此上将做出决定
So the Admiral made a decision.
军需放在第一位
Military needs are a priority.
你们把它们拆了
You stripped them.
为了要配件
You stripped the ships for parts.
我的天
Sweet mother of Artemis.
你们拿走了多少设备?
How much equipment did you take?
把它们的超过速驱动器也拿走了?
You take their jump drives?
把那些人全丢在那里
Left all those people marooned out there?
不是全部
No, not all.
凯恩上将从乘客名单中选定
Adm. Cain looked over the passenger list and she made a decision
有价值的人选
about who was valuable and who wasn't.
轮到斯库拉的时候是最困难的
Scylla was the toughest.
拉尔德同其他的15名男女
Laird and 15 other men and women.
他们都是
They were all...
携家人出游
All traveling with their families,
全家的人
wives, husbands, children.
被选中的人…
The selectees
拒绝离开 有人反抗
refused to go. There was resistance.
所以上头的命令是...
So, the order came down
杀死那些拒绝前来的全家人
to shoot the family of anyone who refused to come.
所以我们就奉命行事
So we did.
我们让两家人靠着舱壁
Two families. We put them up against the bulkhead
然后杀了他们
and we shot them.
空军队长总是有忙不完的事
The CAG's work is never done.
你还好么?
Hi. How're you doing?
你是说除了被降职...
Oh, you mean apart from being demoted,
还为自己的部下做事以外么?
finding myself working for one of my pilots?
好极了 再好不过了
Great. Never better.
你知道我与此事无关  对吧?
You know I had nothing to do with that, right?
从没想过是你的原因
Never thought you did.
我刚去探望了西洛和蒂罗尔
I just checked in on Helo and Tyrol.
他们暂时没事
They're hanging tight for now.
那就好
Good.
帮我策划这次行动
Help me plan this op.
我一直对着这份名单发呆
I've been staring at this roster...
你想装作若无其事一样去执行命令么?
Do you want to just carry on as if nothing's happened?
李  她掌权 我有什么办法?
Lee, she's in command. What do you wanna do?
我们无计可施
There's nothing we can do.
你可能需要一套干净的衣服
I thought you might like a fresh set of clothes.
你上船的时候是否知道自己是赛昂人?
Were you aware of your true nature as a Cylon when you boarded the ship
你认为自己是潜伏者么?
or would you describe yourself as a sleeper agent?
我知道自己是什么人
I knew what I was.
我是一名军人 我要执行任务
I was a soldier. I had a mission, I carried it out.
我本以为任务结束后 我会死
I thought that when it was done, I was going to die.
你们会杀了我
That you would kill me.
我就会… 下载到另一副躯体之中
Then I... Then I would download into a new body.
获得重生
Be reborn.
可你们没杀我
But you didn't kill me.
你们对我的所作所为...
The things you did to me...
他们那样对待你是错误的 罪恶的
What they did to you was wrong, evil.
但我不是他们中的一员
But I'm not one of them.
你要相信我
You have to believe me.
从这一刻开始 你会逐渐好起来的
Things are going to get better for you from this moment on.
我保证
I promise.
我不想好起来 我想死
I don't want things to get better. I want to die.
可你知道你死不了
But you know you can't die.
这你是清楚的  是吧?
You do know that, don't you?
你的思想会传到另一副躯体那里 然后醒过来
Your consciousness will merely transfer, and you'll wake up in another body.
如果把它毁了 就不会了
Not if you destroy that.
什么 这是…
What, this?
这艘船? 告诉我
This ship? Tell me,
这艘船为何如此重要?
what's so important about this ship?
这艘船被赛昂人称作"重生船"
The Cylons call this their Resurrection ship.
我们此刻远离赛昂人的家园
At the moment, we are too far away from the Cylon home world
他们为了使下载正常进行
for the normal downloading process to work.
而造了这艘船
Which is why they built this ship.
它拥有使赛昂人重生的一切必备装置
It contains the entire apparatus necessary for Cylon resurrection.
这支舰队跟踪卡拉狄加
Now, this ship has been traveling with the fleet,
已有几个月的时间
trailing Galactica for the last several months.
就是说它是保障措施
So it's a safety net.
他们死后就回到这里
A place where they fall back to when they die.
如果他们失去了保障措施呢?
And if they lose their safety net...
那任何一个在这里死掉的赛昂人...
Then any Cylon who dies out here...
就死了
Would be dead.
真正意义上的死亡
As in, really dead.
我敢说他们可不会喜欢的
And I dare say they won't like that.
是的  长官
No, sir.
他们甚至会就此停止追赶我们
They might even stop chasing us.
为什么还要冒着不能重生的危险
Why risk getting killed if you can't just wake up all nice and cozy
追我们呢
in a brand-new body?
博士  你找到了…
Doctor, I think you've just identified
银河系中最重要的那艘船
the most important ship in the galaxy.
我的情况时好时坏 但别担心
I have good days and bad days, but don't look so worried,
我又不会今天死掉
I'm not dying today.
我不担心
I wasn't worried.
有什么事么?
What can I do for you?
凯恩确实像你所说的一样
You were right about Cain.
帕伽索斯曾有一支民用舰队
Pegasus had a civilian fleet with her.
15艘船
Fifteen ships.
凯恩把它们拆了  为了要那些配件和补给品
Cain stripped them for parts, supplies,
还有人才
people.
她就是那种人
I wish I could say I was surprised, but it's who she is.
永远都精于算计  你也要这样
She's playing for keeps. You gotta do the same.
你这是怎么了?
What's gotten into you?
什么?
What?
变得好残忍
You've become so bloody-minded.
只要凯恩活着一天
I know that as long as Cain lives,
你的生命就有危险   这我清楚
your survival is at risk. I know that.
你还需要些什么?
What can I get you?
一副新的躯体
A new body.
最好是"复活船"上的…
Perhaps one of those young Cylon models
妙龄女郎
from the Resurrection ship?
我看你不适合做金发美女
I can't see you as a blonde.
会让你大吃一惊的
You'd be surprised.
咱们明天见?
I'll see you tomorrow?
嗯…
Mmm-hmm.
指挥官?
Commander,
她会毫不犹豫地杀了你
she won't hesitate to kill you.
别让她得逞
Don't let her.
咱们从这里出去以后...
You know, when we get out of here,
我要做些改变了
I'm gonna make some changes.
是么?
Yeah?
例如?
Like what?
我和莎伦...
Me and Sharon.
结束了
It's done.
真的结束了 我不能再继续了
I mean, really done. I can't do it anymore.
别理解错了
I mean, don't get me wrong.
中尉  我们所做的一切...
LT, what we did,
如果有类似情况 我不会有丝毫犹豫
I would do again in a heartbeat.
就让一切过去吧
I gotta let it go.
一切都过去了
I so thought I'd let go.
恩
Yeah,
我知道你什么意思了
I know what you mean.
你?
You?
恩  我
Yeah, me.
怎么?  你以为我没怀疑过自己?
What, you think I don't have second thoughts sometimes?
没想过自己是不是疯了?
You think I don't wonder if I'm losing my frakking mind?
我爱的女人却不是女人
I'm in love with a woman I know isn't a woman.
我的孩子...
I'm having a baby that's...
算是什么?  半机器?
That's what, half machine?
你真的爱她  是吧?
You really do love her, don't you?
恩
Yeah.
是的
Yes, I do.
这种感情挥之不去
And I can't let go of it.
但你却能够  割舍
But if you can, let her go.
我们的主要目标 是被赛昂人称作"重生"的船只
Our primary objective is a vessel named Resurrection by the Cylons.
它是由在这一地区
It's guarded by two Base Stars,
追踪我们至今的两艘基地之星把守的
which have been following us throughout this sector.
我们的计划 就是让他们发现我们
Our plan, simply put, is to let them find us.
我们会在这个星系里等它们
We will wait in this system here,
装作采矿
and appear to be conducting mining operations.
当赛昂人派出突袭机的时候
STARBUCK: When the Cylons launch their Raiders,
卡拉狄加就和大部分民用船跳跃走
Galactica and most of the civilians will jump away.
留下一小部分民用船
A small group of civilians will be left behind.
在赛昂人看来 那些船因超光速驱动器出现了故障
To the Cylons, they'll appear to be having trouble
而试图用亚光速进行跳跃
with their FTL drives and attempting to escape at sub-light speed.
突袭机追击诱饵
The Cylon Raiders pursue the civilian decoys,
从而远离了母舰
pulling the Raiders farther away from the Cylon Base Stars as they can.
一旦突袭机被诱饵引开后...
APOLLO: Once the Raiders have been drawn off by the decoys,
卡拉狄加和帕伽索斯 跳跃出来攻击基地之星
Galactica and Pegasus will jump in and attack the Base Stars,
为避免"复活船"跳跃走...
while I jump in in the Blackbird stealth fighter
我会驾驶隐形的飞鸟号 跳跃到它的附近...
and take out the FTL drives
摧毁它的超光速驱动器
on the Resurrection ship, preventing it from jumping away.
为什么不从一开始 就让隐形飞船装载核弹摧毁它?
Why not have the stealth ship carry nukes and destroy it right at the start?
我们做过模拟演习
We ran simulations on that. We determined that the Cylons would detect
在进入隐形飞船的射程之前
the nuclear warheads and destroy the stealth ship
赛昂人就会探测到核弹并摧毁飞船
before it got within weapons range.
当超光速驱动器被摧毁后...
When the FTL is destroyed, Galactica and Pegasus
卡拉狄加与帕伽索斯 将迎战基地之星
will take on the Base Stars,
我们的攻击中队则将追击"复活船"
and our attack squadrons will go after the Resurrection ship itself.
几个中队?
How many squadrons?
全部
All of them.
有何异议吗  指挥官?
Is there a problem, Commander?
我需要些时间来研究一下作战细节
I need time to study the operational details.
请便 我已经研究过了 很满意
Suit yourself. I've gone over the details and I'm satisfied.
我需要你的空军队长留下来 回答我的一些问题
I want your CAG to stay and help me answer some of my questions.
给你一小时  瑟瑞丝
One hour, Thrace.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
打起精神  孩子
Stay focused, son.
杰克  我想派一支海军特遣队到卡拉狄加
Jack, I want to transfer a detachment of Marines to Galactica.
由你来亲自挑选
And I want you to hand-pick them.
完全可靠 忠心耿耿
Completely reliable. Completely loyal.
精兵
Razors.
我要分配给你一项任务  卡拉
I have a mission for you, Kara.
任何事都行 这你是知道的
Anything for you. You know that.
别过早下定论
Don't accept too quickly.
你不会喜欢这项任务
You won't like this one.
我不喜欢
I don't like it.
但我已下定决心 必须这么做
But I've decided that it has to be done.
我也会把你派到卡拉狄加
I'm transferring you to Galactica as well.
我会和阿达玛说你是我的耳目
I'll tell Adama that you're there to be my eyes and ears.
他不会喜欢 他会把你当作是我的间谍
He'll hate it, he'll think you're my spy
而不让你参与出谋划策
and try to freeze you out of decision-making,
但他会接受
but he'll accept it.
在交战的过程中 你要一直留在作战情报中心
Now, I want you to stay in CIC throughout the attack.
留在阿达玛身边
Stay with Adama.
攻击过后...
ADAMA: After the attack is completed,
在你清点完你的驾驶员以后...
and you've accounted for your pilots,
你把战机降落到帕伽索斯上
I want you to land your bird on the Pegasus to report
然后直接到作战情报中心报道
directly to CIC.
带李和你一起去
You'll take Lee with you.
他会掩护你
He'll watch your back.
把陆站队部署在船上的关键位置
Position Marines in key areas throughout the ship and keep a squad
在作战情报中心外留守一个小队
posted just outside CIC.
作战后他们会群情激昂
Now, there will be the normal chaos and emotional high after the attack.
他们会相互称赞 欢庆胜利
They'll be slapping each other on the back, celebrating the victory.
他们会撤掉守卫
That'll keep their guard down.
疏于防范
Security will be lax.
我会通过无线电找你
I will ask for you over the wireless.
我会直接打给你
I will call you directly. And when I have you on the line
当你听到我下令 "执行橙色方案"的时候
and you hear me give the command "Execute case orange"...
当你听我说"垮台"的时候
When you hear me say "Downfall"...
你就示意陆站队 解除阿达玛的指挥权
...you are to signal the Marines to terminate Adama's command.
从阿达玛开始
Start it with Adama.
你就拔出武器
...I want you to pull out your weapon
打爆凯恩上将的头
and shoot Adm. Cain in the head.